Ali Raza

Teacher Pakistan/Business Studies O/A'Levels

O Levels Teacher Pakistan Studies A Levels Business Studies

Experience

potential

Teacher A'Levels (Business Studies)

The City School Sahiwal - August 2019 to January 2020



- Promote high standards of behaviour by encouraging a positive, proactive approach to study and build productive relationships with students
- Assess, record and monitor the progress of all students according to faculty guidelines in order to provide accurate information to parents in a variety of forms, as and when necessary
- Maintain materials and resources as needed

Teacher O'Levels (Pakistan Studies)

Beaconhouse Margalla Campus, Islamabad - November 2018 to July 2019

- Establish clear objectives for all lessons, units, and projects, and communicate those objectives to students.
- Prepare, administer, and grade tests and assignments to evaluate students' progress
- Adapt teaching methods and instructional materials to meet students' varying needs and
- Plan and conduct activities for a balanced program of instruction, demonstration, and work time that provides students with opportunities to observe, question, and investigate.
- Guide and counsel students with adjustment and/or academic problems, or special academic interests.

Teacher O'Levels (Pakistan Studies)

Benchmark School System, Islamabad - August 2018 to November 2018

- Planning lessons and classes in detail, incorporating several techniques and strategies to suit different learning styles and capabilities
- Establish and enforce rules for behavior and procedures for maintaining order among students.
- Establish clear objectives for all lessons, units, and projects, and communicate these objectives to students.
- Prepare materials and classrooms for class activities.
- Enhancing familiarity with digital platforms to facilitate learning (such as Edmodo and Khan Academy)
- Attend professional meetings, educational conferences, and teacher training workshops to maintain and improve professional competence.

Teacher O'Levels (Pakistan Studies)

The City School Okara - February 2015 to June 2018 - Pakistan

- The City School's (abbreviated as TCS) is an independent Pakistani for-profit education company which operates 192 English medium primary and secondary schools in 53 cities across Pakistan along with joint venture projects in UAE, Saudi Arabia, Philippines, Malaysia and Bangladesh. It is Pakistan's second-largest private education firm, with a total of 65,000 students enrolled as of 2016, with average tuition fees of about \$200 a month.
- Adapt teaching methods and instructional materials to meet students' varying needs and interests
- Prepare, administer, and grade tests and assignments to evaluate students'progress.



28 years old

Contact

- □ rao.ali.raza09@gmail.com
- ↑ +92-333-2154034

- Confer with parents or guardians, other teachers, counselors, and administrators to resolve students'behavioral and academic problems.
- Meet with other professionals to discuss individual students' needs and progress. Attend staff meetings and serve on staff committees as required.
- Prepare students for later grades by encouraging them to explore learning opportunities and to persevere with challenging tasks.

Parent Relation Officer

B S S

Beaconhouse Educational Complex - February 2014 to February 2015 - Islamabad - Pakistan

- To Keep Record of Student fee, Payable, Recoverable and Paid.
- To assist in correspondence with parents. Result compilation(In-house &CIE)
- Draft correspondence as required or on own initiative for administrative processes. Coordination with the concerned departments for placement of advertisements.
- To establish an interaction with 200+ students and the parents for all info and gueries.
- Make travel arrangements including preparation of travel authorizations, travel reservations, other travel related requirements.
- Maintain and organize and update filing system for correspondence, documents, computer
 office files, reference materials.

Parent Relation Officer



Beaconhouse School System - February 2014 to February 2015

To Keep Record of Student fee,Payable,Recoverable and Paid.
To assist in correspondence with parents,result compilation(Inhouse & CIF)

Draft correspondence as required or on own initiative for administrative processes. Coordination with the concerned departments for placement of advertisements To establish an interaction with 200+ students and the parents for all info and gueries

Make travel arrangements including preparation of travel authorizations, travel reservations, other travel related requirements

Maintain and organize and update filing system for correspondence, documents, computer office files, reference materials,

Recovery Officer



United Bank Ltd - October 2011 to February 2014 - Pakistan

- Visits and collect payment through proper working on all accounts allocated through SRs request according to SBP Fair Debt Collections guidelines and need to visit on assigned cases of EAMU verification aspects which will be forwarded by concerning Supervisor or DRM on allocated neighbour hoods.
- Give daily feedback on accounts visited to his concerned DRM.
- Properly maintain all visit reports and ensure that 3 days TAT on cash slips should be maintained at all times.
- While meeting with the customers provide better solutions to customers whose cash flows are disturbed.

Customer Service Representative



Mobilink (An Orascom Company) - July 2011 to October 2011 - Pakistan

• Receiving Calls for problem resolution from Cellular phone Connection users in call centre.

- Working on CRM model sys (SIEBEL & CHRIS) to eradicate issues in compliance of the project Problem resolution.
- Record maintenance Call Data entry Categorization Authority issued in sys.
- Tougher assignments to be forwarded to Team Leader through sys ID.
- Full adherence to quality protocol of the company on recorded calls.
- Gel in with the team of problem resolver.

Customer Service Representative

Stoneage Int. (BPO) - June 2010 to June 2011 - Pakistan



- Sstoneage Int's customized solutions include inbound and outbound telemarketing and true business process outsourcing (BPO) that typically enhance or replace in-house operations. Serving over 40 clients in the U.S. Canada, and the U.K. Stoneage Int acts as a seamless extension of its clients' operations, providing dramatic cost efficiencies and measurable quality and performance improvements.
- Managing a team of 6 callers and Teachers Recitation Teachings.
- Search of readers and learners through International calling.
- A fully devoted organization of Online resolution providers to Quran.
- Defining new needs of the organization.
- Full adherence to Country Laws for Telecommunication Maintaining a safe and secure work environment.

Skills

Classroom Management

- Maintaining Discipline
- Active Learning
- Assesment Making



- Group Work/Pair Work
- Subject Command
- · Spoken English



School Based Training, Courses and Workshops

- PGCC [The City School]
- INSET [The City School]
- Child Protection Programme [Beaconhouse School System]



- MOOT [The City School]
- APTIS [The City School]
- BTTP [Beaconhouse School System]



Professional Development Trainings

- CAIE AS & A Levels 9609 ★★★★☆ Extention
- CAIE O Levels 2059/P1 Extention
- CAIE O Levels 2059/P2 Extention

IT Skills

- OS Windows
- MS Excel



MS Word



About Me

I have worked at four of the best schools of my country, in the past 6 years. During this time I found my grounds and learned what worked the best on each student. It is an extraordinary time and this is what i want to do in long term. I feel that my role is to facilitate my students to enrich their learning experience so that they can make a earth a better place for everyone.

Testimonials

Ali was in my team during his tenure at Mobilink and Ifound him a good teamplayer, a very good listenerand andriod problem solve, being an inquisitive person he is shows his learning aptitude.He surely was an asset to my team. Ayaz Awan Manager Call Center Operations Brightlite Pakistan

I have known Mr.Ali Raza for two years and found him a highly efficient and professional team member in his tenure.He's one of those people at your work you can always count on and have kept an excellent record of meeting deadlines and tasks assigned sometimes even on eleventh hour. In short he's an asset to any organization with leading qualities. Noor ul Ain Senior Mistress The City School

In professional environments ,what one manager needs the most is loyalty, loyalty with organization and work. Ali was loyal with his work and he proved to be a great resource for the station where he was deployed. He has an extraordinary quality of organizing his portfolio and then implementing his plans accordingly which was rarely seen for an entrant position. Muhammad Khalid District Recovery Manager United Bank Ltd

Education

M.Phil(Marketing)

Preston University

November 2015 to August 2018

GPA: 3.9 CGPA

Thesis: Role of Brand and Endorser Credibility on Brand Equity of Cell Phone in Pakistan

MA(International Relations)

University of Sargodha

November 2016 to July 2017 2nd Div : 546/1000 Marks

MA(Pakistan Studies)

University of Sargodha

November 2017 to July 2018 1st Div : 646/1000 Marks

M.Com

BZU,Sahiwal

October 2012 to June 2015

CGPA: 3.49

B.Com

F.G College of Commerce H-8/4,Islamabad

2008 to August 2010 1st Div : 919/1500 Marks

Fsc

F.G Q uaid- e- Azam College, Rawalpindi

2006 to 2008

1st Div: 705/1100 Marks

SSC

F.G Boys Secondary School, Rawalpindi Cantt

2004 to 2006

1st Div: 810/1050 Marks

Interests

Results

- 3A*,1A, 3Bs, 3Cs [May June 2019]
- Number of students appeared: 10
- 7A,3B,1C [May June 2018]
- Number of students appeared: 11
- 3A*,2A,5B,3C,1D,1E [May June 2017]